Guide to the Elinor Cogswell Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Elinor Cogswell papers
circa 1896-1976
SC0293
Cogswell, Elinor.
0.5 Linear feet and 1 microfilm reel
Correspondence, manuscripts, articles, photograph album and photographs, diploma, memorabilia, and diaries (1912-1916, 1931) largely pertaining to her association with Stanford University. Correspondence includes letters from David Lamson, 1933-1937, partially concerning his prison experiences; letters from Prof. David Harris, 1968-73, concerning his research and experiences in England, death of his wife Christina, and his return to Palo Alto; and one letter from Kay I. Kitagawa, 1943, concerning experiences of a Nisei in the Armed Services. Other correspondents include Albert Guérard, Herbert Hoover, E.B. "Sam" MacDonald, and Edith R. Mirrielees.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Estate of Elinor Cogswell, 1983.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Elinor Cogswell received her A.B. in English at Stanford in 1916, her M.A. in 1917; she was a journalist with the PALO ALTO TIMES and served as editor from 1938 to 1954. She was one of the first women to become a Stanford Associate; she died in 1983 at the age of 90.
Description of the Collection
Correspondence, manuscripts, articles, photograph album and photographs, diploma, memorabilia, and diaries (1912-1916, 1931) largely pertaining to her association with Stanford University. Correspondence includes letters from David Lamson, 1933-1937, partially concerning his prison experiences; letters from Prof. David Harris, 1968-73, concerning his research and experiences in England, death of his wife Christina, and his return to Palo Alto; and one letter from Kay I. Kitagawa, 1943, concerning experiences of a Nisei in the Armed Services. Other correspondents include Albert Guérard, Herbert Hoover, E.B. "Sam" MacDonald, and Edith R. Mirrielees.
Access Terms
Cogswell, Elinor.; Guérard, Albert Léon, 1880-1959.; Harris, David, (David W. Clancy), 1900-1975.; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964; Kitagawa, Kay I.; Lamson, David.; MacDonald, Emanuel B.; Mirrielees, Edith R., (Edith Ronald), 1878-1962.; Stanford University; Albums.; Photoprints.; World War, 1939-1945--Japanese Americans.
Collection Contents
- PERSONAL PAPERS
  - Correspondence from David Harris, 1968-1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence from Dave Lamson, 1933-1937 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence from Norris, 1934-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: A-Z, 1935-1960 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Kegley, Paul: letter to Prof. Robinson, re Frank Angell, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - E. Cogswell, writings, 1908-1968 and undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Songs known by F.A.C. [Fred Cogswell ?] (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Diplomas, 1916, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Senior Week program, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Commencement items, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - LSJU alumni matters, 1963-1973 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Photograph album, 1916-1920 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- HISTORICAL MATERIALS
  - Articles about Stanford and Stanford people (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Bark, Eleanor Carlton, Escondito cottage brochure, circa 1959 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Clippings and newspapers re Stanford, circa 1896-1968 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - LSJU programs and miscellaneous items (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Palo Alto, brochure, circa 1910 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Photographs (Stanford scenes) (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - ___________ (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Regnery, Dorothy F., "An 1801 Russian Cannon," pamphlet, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - The Tall Tree, 1954-1976 (publication of the Palo Alto Historical Society) (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Diaries of Elinor Cogswell, 1912-1916 and 1931
General note
Diaries (1912-1916, 1931) are on microfilm.